[music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat.
[music]
[music] Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Good evening, good day everybody and
welcome to the 301st
episode of the Ask Ask a widget show. I
hope you're all doing great. Let's see
who all is there on the live chat. This
is going to be a session in which I am
going to take questions that you have
asked in the comments with with the hash
ask ajit. So I'm going to take history
questions today that you have asked in
the comments and if there is time I will
take some live chat questions at the
end. Let's see who is there on the live
chat. Rahul G good evening online. Good
to see you. Good to see you. Sar Mahajan
feminists Abu Singh Rahul Dunak.
Um Sukun Vacher. Okay. Aayush Singh
Pranam. Shria Smitra is here from
Moscow. Good to see you. Shas wise
idiot. [laughter]
Achedin is here. Arian rocking gaming
animals for laugh is here from Mumbai.
Good to see you sir. Amisha [snorts]
Mishra. Hello ma'am. Gorabkar Ahan.
Swami Jin is here from Jaipur. Snapdil
Mishra. Hello Ankit G. Hello Vidyman
good evening ma'am Sumesh0 069 Avin
Mystic SK JSK Jashri Krishna G Hit Patel
good to see you Sin 439 we are so back
aren't we are back uh geopolitical is
here from Indor good to see you sir
Vishnu valerous evening to you Abida
Singh woohoo
uh feminist Jay Baba Pashwaram random
skull Jri Krishna Hersai hello random
shorts kall animals for laugh brian
kabon
GK Field Strong Man Random Shorts Chat
DSP Shreas DK Sandy 97 Namaste K22ish
official Priyanka Javalia from Gorga
good to see you ma'am good to see you
Gulu Rajput Jay Bhavani
um KK family uh
from Greece uh one second hello from
Greece I'm not sure it'll take me some
time I'll okay I'll not try to do that
but good to See you. Uh my my Greek is a
little rusty. I can still read but it
takes time. Chat DSP Sandy Ouo is here.
Samyak Space. Good evening. Ashwani
Sunil Seagel. God was alive. Dak Spade
Practics Gamer Indi Achilles Mayur Nyak
Gulu Raj Rajput Miran Nam Bula. Okay.
Namaste
Gok Spade Dak Akuma.
Um, Suman Potam City Saturn 88 Namaskar
Sudhir Kumar event countdown Rahul Meta
Sunil Seagel Feel Strong Man Staint
Crocodile
[laughter]
okay and everybody else I won't be able
to greet you all individually as you
know but uh okay who else we have Bumi
Aditya Gupta Partapati Miranam etc
wooden armor PK I'm a painter Char
[laughter]
[gasps] Sid Jane Bruce Bruce Wayne,
Sudhir, Daksh. All right. Okay. Let's
get going with the questions otherwise
I'm going to I'm going to greet you all
day and I would um request you all to
not take to not take super chats today
cuz I'm going to take questions that you
all have asked in the comments. So I'll
take those today. Let us get going with
the questions. What is question number
one that we have today? What questions
have I picked? Let me see. It's been a
Let's see where where where are the
questions? Here we are.
What's question number one? Here we go.
Ritik Pawar says, "Why did no Indian
kings perform the ashwame, the yagna
after 350 AD? Samudra Gupta did that in
350 AD. What's the deal? Why did no
Indian kings do this?" Well, first of
all, it's not entirely accurate to say
that no one did that after 350 AD. Samud
Gupta, the great Gupta emperor certainly
did that and he was a fantastic
conqueror as we know. But we had various
rulers from various dynasties who did
conduct who did perform this ancient
ritual between 350 AD and uh around the
11th century AD. For example, Vakatak
rulers, Chola rulers, Chalukia ruler,
cha chalukia rulers, various Rajput
rulers etc. And the last ruler that is
known to have performed this yagna is
Savai J Singh II of J J J J J J J J J J
J J J J J J J J J J Jipur in the 18th
century who did it twice.
So you have more rulers after some Gupta
who did do this perform this very
ancient ritual dating back to the riga
right but yeah it's it's it's no longer
performed why is that that the case
right so let us understand what the
ashwa made the yagna was all about what
was this
ritual
what was this ancient ritual what was it
all about it involved an ashwa
a force. So the ashwamed ritual was
performed by kings or emperors. Here's
what was done.
So according to the shastrat of the
vedas, according to Vic rituals and
prescriptions, a young powerful male
horse would be selected, a stallion
and that horse would need to have
certain characteristics. So the right
kind of horse, young powerful male
stallion was selected. And the various
uh Vic rituals were done with the
stallion. Various pujas and vidhis etc
were done on the stallion. And then on a
very specifically chosen date
the stallion was released.
Go wherever you feel like going go. And
it's not just like the stallion was
simply released. the entire
not the entire military but a
significant portion of the king's
military would accompany the stallion
wherever the stallion chose to go. So
the child stallion was free to go where
wherever he wanted. He would not be
restrained. He would not be guided. he
would be allowed to go wherever he chose
to go and the military would simply
accompany him at a at at a respectable
decent distance.
Okay? And this process would go on for
one year. One full year, the stallion
would wander wherever he wanted to go.
Now, here's the deal. The stallion would
go into neighboring territories, into
the territories of neighboring kings,
for example. Then when the stallion
enters the territory of a neighboring
king, that king would have a crucial
choice.
Do I allow the stallion to come into my
territory or do I oppose him? If I allow
the stallion to wander through my
territory and I don't oppose the
stallion, then I'm acknowledging the
suzarenti
of the king who has performed the ashwid
yagna, which means that I become his
vasal.
If I oppose him, I have to deal with his
military.
And a king who would have a weak
military would not dare to do an ashwame
the yagna.
So it was about expanding your
territory. It was about forcing your
neighbors
[clears throat] to to acknowledge your
superiority and your overlordship
and their vasalhood.
That way you would very rapidly gain
more vasals or you would defeat your you
know those who dared to stand up against
you. So this process went on for a full
year.
Okay. And obviously you would need a
powerful military to accompany the horse
and those that all those soldiers would
have to be supported logistically and
and so on. It's a pretty big undertaking
military. It's a full year-long military
campaign essentially that we are talking
about. But the pretext is the journey of
a horse. Okay. So after a year is over,
the horse would then be brought back to
the king's capital and then there would
be um further set of religious rituals
and ceremonies that would go on for
about 25 days. [clears throat] The king
who had released the horse and now he's
got the horse back. He would wear only
you know clothes made from the skin of a
black buck.
Okay. And he would only sleep on the
floor on the ground not on a bed. And he
would do various yagnas and various
rituals for 25 or so days. And then on
the once that is done the horse would be
brought in and the main yagna would
happen and it would not just be the the
horse himself
but several hundred other animals.
Um the number I recall is 609 animals
apart from the horse.
And um the horse the ashwa would then be
sacrificed
animal sacrifice. It would be suffocated
to death and then various rituals would
then be performed. The the king's
principal wife would also perform some
rituals along with the king or
separately from the king. Uh the details
we need need not go into. There is some
controversy about that because of
various uh western mistransations.
That's a different story. So see when
you are a king that's that powerful you
would not have a single wife. would have
multiple wives, but there would be one
principal wife, the principal queen, the
main queen. And she would perform um the
ceremonies that were required.
And then the the horse would be
quartered or or divided into various
pieces and the flesh would be cooked and
various other animals would also be
sacrificed and their flesh would also be
offered to the gods and so on. And the
king would then give gigantic donations
of gold and silver to to hundreds of of
uh brahmans, priests, rishies, bullies
etc. And all the rituals would have to
be done as per strict rigidic standards.
All the mantra all the mantra erans have
to had to be done properly and so on. Uh
and and and a lot of offerings had to be
offered to Agni to the gods via Agni.
hundreds of kilograms of mong beans and
and barley and and so many other things
and obviously heaps and heaps of gold
and silver coins.
So imagine
how expensive this is and how risky this
is.
First of all, you are conducting a
year-long military campaign,
and you may be very powerful, which is
why you dare to do it. But then you
would have to send a significant portion
of your military on a campaign wherever
the horse leads them for a year. You
would have to supply them. You would
have to give them all the logistics you
need, they need. It's an expensive
thing, very expensive thing to send an
army on a military campaign for a full
year. That's number one. Secondly,
all those heaps and heaps of gold and
silver coins. Who's going to pay for
that? Super expensive. Then you have to
um donate donate all of those to various
brahinss, various priests and and the
people. You would have to to procure
hundreds of kilos of ghee and and moon
beans and and barley and and all kinds
of other things.
So it was risky and it was extremely
extremely expensive to perform the
Ashume the yagna. That's number one.
That's number one. So only very powerful
kings or emperors could afford to do
this or even risk to do it. If you were
a small king somewhere with a small army
and a small economy, how on earth would
you do the ashamed yagna? If your horse
wandered into the territory of a much
powerful ne much more powerful neighbor,
well, you were in be deep trouble. If
the horse was stopped and you did not
then fight that king, then you were
humiliated and your own people would not
respect you. So, it did not make any
sense for a king who was not powerful to
do that. And if you were really
powerful, then you would incur a
tremendous amount of expenditure. But
the riskreward thing was also great
because you would end up gaining a lot
of territory. that also worked. Yeah. So
that's the economics and that's the
riskreward uh you know uh calculations
of the ashwamed yagna. Uh now in the
past 1,000 years we increasingly came
upon more and more progressive foreign
occupation starting with the uh the Turk
Delhi Sultteranet for a while. Then
there was the Muggal Kingdom which
eventually became a Muggal Empire under
Aurang. And then you had the various uh
European uh occupiers of India who uh
you know took away the sovereignty who
who defeated various Indian kings and
empires including the Marata Empire
eventually and we lost sovereignty and
once you lose sovereignty how on earth
do you do the Ashamed Yagna? Today we
are a secular nation. our culture, our
religion is is not it's it's you know
it's it's given a secondass status in
the country. So today it's not well the
shame the no longer has any relevance
right. So that's how this this great
ancient uh practice you know went out of
usage.
So until the next Ashwave Yagna does uh
does happen, India is well if if
whenever the Ashwave the Yagna happens
again that will be the revival of Indian
civilization the proper Indian
civilization not the fake Hins Indian
civilization in which you know you don't
do hinsa you don't do animal sacrifices
and all the ashwi yagna was a
full-fledged animal sacrifice yagna from
the vic times from the oldest vic times
rigidic times your ancestors ate meat
your ancestors performed animal
sacrifices and more than animal
sacrifices
and then what happened is that you know
what that's another factor as well
Buddhism and ginism so one of the things
that Ashoke the great Ashoke emperor
Ashoke did was
he transformed this obscure fringe
religious path dharmic path into a
global phenomenon Buddhism right and
Buddhism was all about nonviolence
and nonviolence kinds of kind of appeals
to the Indian psyche to some extent for
some reason and because the Buddhists uh
espoused nonviolence
the
the brahinss
who performed vic rituals they were then
branded as animal killers
and that kind of put them at a very
disadvantageous position in society. For
several hundred years, Buddhism became
the dominant dharmic path in India.
[clears throat] So to adapt
strategically, tactically, the Brahmans
had to become even more nonviolent than
the Buddhists. The Buddhists still ate
meat. The Brahmans became completely
vegetarian,
right?
And because of that eventually something
different crept into what we call
Hinduism which was uh you know
Vic tradition itself evolved as a
response to the Buddhist challenge. As a
response to that Vic tradition evolved
to prefer symbolic sacrifice over
literal sacrifice.
For example, we have this this tradition
of cracking coconuts,
not green coconut coconuts, dry ripe
coconuts. What do dry ripe coconuts look
like? Let me show you what they look
like.
Give me a second. Let's Google it. Okay.
What does a dry ripe coconut look like?
All right. Here we go. Ripe coconut.
What's it look like?
It looks like this. But what about that?
Why does it look like that? What does
the cracking of a coconut symbolize? It
essentially symbolizes
human sacrifice.
See there are pl there are various gods
and goddesses who need to be who who
require certain kinds of offerings
especially the kulis of of warriors
like kali like da like chamunda if you
go to the ancient temples of these great
goddesses I assure you certain things
happened in the past that are no longer
legal today in those temples so to
replace
those practices with something that's
more acceptable and palatable to our
soft-hearted Hindus of today. We have
replaced those practices with the
cracking of coconuts.
So our society evolved and it became
very vegetarian, very soft, very
nonviolent, very ains, very Gandhian and
Vic tradition itself evolved to prefer
symbolic sacrifice over literal
sacrifice. And today if we talk about
the ashwam the yagna and and the actual
rituals involved in that most Indians
will be like no no no our ancestors
would never have done such things. So
that's the problem. We have become a
civilization of softies,
right?
Of carb eaters, carb maxers. We don't
need protein anymore. We don't perform
the great old Vic rituals anymore. And
that's the problem anyhow. So that's the
reason why the ashamed the yagna is no
longer performed for these multiple
reasons. One is for an occupation. The
second is the secularization and of
India and the destruction of our
civilization and the destruction of
Hinduism from India and the relegation
of Hinduism to secondass status in
India. And thirdly is all of these
things the evolution of Hindu society
itself and the I'm [laughter]
the the the the
softening
I'm [laughter]
I'm searching for a polite word here.
Yeah. [clears throat] Whatever's
happened right that I described. Okay.
[laughter]
Okay. Next, next question. Next
question.
Swapnil Mishra says, "Why is the
Algerian war of independence considered
the bloodiest decolonization war in
Africa? And what factors made the
conflict so violent?"
Algeria.
Does anybody even know about what
happened in Algeria?
the dis the the the ghastliest of wars,
freedom struggles that happened in
Africa, it happened in Algeria. So
what's the deal?
What's the history?
So Algeria, in case some of you are not
aware, we will have to consult the map
which is a practice that I have
introduced into Indian society. Well,
here we go.
Here's the map. We going to look at
where Algeria is situated. So we go
westwards of India. We cross the Arabian
Peninsula. We cross we go west of Egypt.
Then you have Libya and then you have
Algeria. This large North African nation
which is mostly empty desert down south
but the the u major population centers
are up north. Right? You have the city
of Alers, you have the city of
and many others.
So uh that is Algeria and if you go
north of Algeria, if you cross the
Mediterranean Sea, then you reach
France, the country of France. And
that's what we're talking about. We're
talking about Algeria and its struggle
to free itself of French occupation. Now
the polite word in European and modern
society is colonialism.
It was French colonization just like it
was British colonization of India. That
word colonization, it masks a brutal
reality which is foreign occupation and
plunder.
It's occupation, not colonization. So
the Algerians fought to free themselves
of French occupation. Now what's the
history of this French occupation of
Algeria? When did that happen?
So
it began
somewhere around 1830.
Around 1830, the French
uh invaded
Algeria and they captured various parts
of Algeria which were at the northern
fringes of Africa, the the Mediterranean
coastline of Algeria.
Okay. Um and the Algerians put up
significant strong resistance. There was
this Amir Abu Abdul Abdul Abdul Bakr or
something his name was. You can look up
the actual name. the great uh Algerian
freedom fighter from the 1830s and
1840s.
Um so he fought the French for close to
171 18 years and he put up a very strong
resistance against the French but
eventually by about 1848 the French were
able to capture him
and send him into exile or whatever they
did to him. So he is taken out of
action. He is not executed by the French
but he's captured and sent into exile. I
think he was buried in Damascus in Syria
um when he died and sometime in the 20th
century his body was exumed and brought
back to Algeria against his wishes. He
wanted to be buried in in in Damascus.
Anyway, that's a that's a digression. So
uh the the the Amir is defeated,
captured and then the French colonize
uh Algeria after the defeat of the uh of
the Amir and the and the indigenous
resistance against French occupation. So
that happens in I think 1847 1848 around
that time. You can look up the exact
dates, right?
And once that
that struggle is over and it's defeated,
the French then what they did is they
did not declare Algeria as a French
colony. They declared Algeria as an
integral part of France. It's an
integral part of France. It's not a
colony. It's France itself.
It's an integral part of France. And
then what the French did is that they
started this policy of settling
Europeans in Algeria mainly French but
also spa Spanish people and Italians and
and people from Malta as well. So
Europeans were settled over time in
Algeria beginning around 1848 all the
way until the 20th century until the
1940s
and
uh these uh Europeans were called
Pinoir, black feet or whatever in
French. Um
so over time
the f the European population of Alge
Algeria uh became about 15 10 to 15% of
the Algerian population
and they became um
almost like the majority population in
some cities like Alger like in it was
like more than 50% was European in Alger
it was about 30 35% and other cities it
was like that in the northern coast line
of Africa
So close to a million roughly a million
Europeans were settled in Algeria which
formed about 10 to 15% of Algeria's
population and the Algerians were were
systematically repressed. There was this
war that was conducted against them.
They were relegated to secondass status
in their own country. Um many of them
were sent you know the French military,
army, air force, everything was used
against them. uh there were lots of
killings by about 1900 almost a million
Algerians may have died okay uh because
of French uh policies let's say
um so there was a deal now fast forward
to 1945
the second world war war is over it has
just ended and many Algerians had fought
for France does this remind you of thing
India was again under British occupation
and many Indians fought for Britain in
the in the first and second world wars.
Why did Indians fight for Britain? Did
did they see the British as their
masters?
Did they see themselves as owing some
loyalty to the British? No, it was a
job. There was no job available in
India. So lots of people became soldiers
and they fought just to provide for the
families. Similarly, many Algerians
fought for the French. So the French
they created this two-t tire system in
Algeria. Similar to the uh similar to
the South African apathide system,
the French and the Europeans were the
first class citizens. And the Algerians,
the natives were second-ass citizens who
did not have many of the rights and
privileges that the Europeans had. and
some Algerians who had become um
franophones who had who had uh you know
assimilated into French culture and who
had become uh you could say servants of
the French government uh they were given
more rights a small small minority of
people. So by 1945
sometime in May the second world war is
over. The European theater is over.
Hitler is dead. Um
and then many of the Algerians who had
fought for France they started
demonstrating in Algeria
asking for equal rights asking for
French citizenship because Algerians did
not have French citizenship even though
Algeria was technically according to
France an integral part of France. So
Algerians wanted French citizenship.
They wanted equal rights and they
protested and demonstrated and the
French police opened fire on them. Bang,
bang, bang.
And then there were riots and and the
the entire machinery of the French
government was deployed against them.
Army, police, military, air force, navy,
everything. About 2 million Algerians
were sent into concentration camps. And
here is the problem. By by 1945 there
were about a million European origin
people living in Alia right but they had
not come in recently. There were third
or fourth generation
people who lived there. They had been
living there for three four generations.
They regarded Algeria as their homeland
because their grandparents and their
great-grandparents had been born there.
So for them
any prospect of the Algerians asking
them to leave was an existential threat.
So they fought and they were supported
by the fed government. So you have this
situation which is kind of a civil war
like thing maybe war of independence
maybe a war of occupation whatever you
want to call it. So about 2 million
Algerians are sent into concentration
camps. Hundreds of thousands of them are
killed by the French military. Maybe
tens of thousands whatever the numbers
are. You know there's a big controversy
about what the actual numbers are. So it
if you ask the French it will be one set
of numbers. It if you ask somebody else
it will be if you ask the Algerians it
will be a different set of numbers. Uh
so the war the proper war of
independence starts about 80 about 19
56 56 1956
when Shah the Gaul is the uh was the
leader of France and it went on all the
way until 1962.
Um
and uh it was brutal. The Algerian
freedom fighters even killed Algerians
who were suspected of being either
neutral or being collaborators with the
French. Tens of thousands of people died
like this. Either killed by the French
or killed by the freedom fighters.
People caught in the crossfire. People
who were sent into concentration camps
and starved there or brutalized there.
And the the the French described the war
of independence as a as a campaign of
terrorism. And you know that's how it
was. It was brutal. It was barbaric. It
was it was nasty. But by 18 but by 1962
the French decided that we have to leave
now. So the French withdraw from Algeria
but they sign a set of accords with the
Algerian government that takes power.
According to that accord um France
retains access to certain parts of
Algeria until until 1965. So the French
continued even after Algeria became
independent the French continued to do
nuclear tests in the Algerian Sahara
desert.
about 13 or 15 or so nuclear tests the
French did there. Uh and after the
French left
there was a large number of of people
who had who had fought for France
who had served in the French military or
government or whatever who had worked
for France. Now there were reprisals
against these people by the new Algerian
government and maybe 130,000 of them
were killed. So that was it. If you look
at the cumulative death toll, if you
look at the figures that Algeria
gives us, according to those figures,
more than 5 million Algerians died
between 1830 and 1960 to 1965.
more than 5 million Algerians. They're
considered to be martyrs obviously and
uh tens of thousands of Europeans and
French also died. So it was brutal. Uh
there's no war of independence in Africa
that has been this brutal, right? It was
obviously less brutal than the 1857
Indian War of Independence in which way
more Indians died, but that's a whole
different story. So you can't compare
the two. But yeah, so that's why the
Algerian War of Independence is called
the bloodiest decolonization war in
Africa. And these are the factors that
made the conflict so violent, you know.
Right. Okay. Next. Amisha says,
"Although colonized by Spain for over
300 years, the Philippines never became
a Spanish-sp speakaking nation unlike
Latin America." Why is that? Okay, let's
once again go to the map and figure out
where is this place called the
Philippines. So, we know where India is.
Now, we have to go eastwards. So we go
eastwards from the Bay of Bengal, the
Andan Sea, the straight of Mala. We
cross over into the Champa Samudra which
is currently called the South China Sea.
And here west of Indonesia we have the
Philippines. This big archipelago south
of Taiwan
and north of Sulawesi, Indonesia in
Brunai. That is uh Philippines pretty
large archipilago.
So the Philippines were colonized by
Spain
but the Philippines never became a
Spanish speaking nation unlike Latin
American nations of today. Why is that
the case right? That's what we have to
understand. Now first of all understand
Philippines is not really very far from
the endosphere. It used to be part of
the endosphere. What is this endosphere
that I talk about? The Indosphere was
all of those uh cultures or or or
kingdoms or or regions of Asia that were
primarily influenced by Indian culture
by Hindu culture. So the Philippines
were very much part of the Indosphere.
They were at some at at a point in time
vasals of the Chola Empire and the kings
and rulers of the Philippines were
called Rajas.
So when the Spaniards arrived in the
Philippines around when the Europeans
arrived in the Philippines in the 16th
century, the kings that ruled in the
Philippines were called Rajas. One of
the great Rajas was Lapu Lapu and these
were Hindus
and they you know Sanskrit des Sanskrit
inscriptions have been uh discovered in
the Philippines. So the Philippines was
part of the Indosphere. So let's quickly
understand the context. 1492 what
happens? You have Columbus stumbling
upon the Americas and believing that he
has reached India which he was looking
for. That's 1492. 1498 we have Vasco
Gama who arrives in India who discovers
India apparently because nobody had
discovered it. That's 1498.
Um in 1520 1521 you have the fall of the
uh Aztec triple alliance which which
whose capital was Tokitlan present day
Mexico City and the Spaniards destroyed
the Aztec Empire in Latin America.
Hernand Cortez was the barbarian in
charge of that in the 1530s all the way
to the 1570s. You have the Spanish
destruction of the Inca Empire in Peru.
Franchesco Pitzaro was the barbarian
responsible for that. So that's what's
happening in the world around this time
in the 16th century, right? And then
um it's around 1500 or something 1500
something that Magelan the Portuguese
explorer discovers the Philippines
because nobody had discovered them and
he fights the the Filipino Raja Lapu
Lapu I believe and he's killed. He's
killed. Um then
the Spaniards
they then uh reach the Philippines
and they start colonizing the
Philippines slowly gradually and it
begins around the 1560s or so right and
this process of colonization goes on for
like like Amisha says more than 300
years until 1898 when you have the
SpanishAmerican war which the Americans
win. So that's when the American
colonization of the Philippines begins
in 1898. So from the 1560s all the way
to 1898 you have the Spanish
colonization of the Philippines and
Philippines the Philippines were ruled
out of Mexico which was then called New
Spain. Okay. Um and in uh in the 1820s
Mexico became independent and once that
happened the Philippines were
administered from Madrid in Spain.
So now the question is why did
the Philippines never become a
Spanish-sp speakaking region? Why is
that? Multiple regions multiple reasons.
So the Philippines like we saw in the
map is a big cluster of hundreds of
islands. It's a it's a vast archipilago
and because you have this kind of
geography you're going to have a lot of
diversity there. If you go to the
Philippines you will find there's more
than 100 different languages that's
spoken there. One of some of the major
ones are Tagalog and so on but you have
hundreds of different languages spoken
there and uh it was very difficult to
kind of unify everything under one
language. So uh one of the principal um
objectives of the Spaniards was to
convert
convert the Hindus of the Philippines to
Christianity.
So the Spanish missionaries they decided
that instead of teaching everybody
Spanish, we will divide ourselves into
various groups and go to various
islands, we will learn the native
language and we will convert them to
Christianity by speaking the local
languages.
that is the tactic or the strategy that
they adopted.
So they never tried to impose Spanish
for the longest time until the 19th
century
uh on the Philippines. So eventually
because of the Spanish military
superiority and the and the overwhelming
um arm twisting power and brutality and
all that they were able to convert the
Filipinos uh the people of the
Philippines from Hinduism to uh
Christianity. It's only sometime in the
19th century that they that they imposed
a Spanish language education system on
the Philippines and tried to instruct
everybody in in the Spanish language and
um you know have everyone adopt the
Spanish language did not quite have
sufficient time to work right even today
in India a lot of people can't still
speak English even though we have been
called
right? I'm back. Okay. So even today a
lot of people in India still can't speak
English. Uh even though we have been
colonized by the East India Company
since what 1747
1757 more than 200 years and after 1947
we apparently are independent but we
have further imposed English on everyone
and still the majority of Indians don't
speak English right after like more than
three centuries of English presence
significant English presence. So the
Spanish did not have sufficient time to
be present in in the Philippines and
impose their language. All they were
able to do is to make all Filipinos
adopt Spanish names. Fernando Marcos,
email the Marcos and so on so forth,
right? That sort of thing.
Uh and then the Americans took over
after defeating the the the Spanish in
1898 and then you know the Philippines
became an American colony and then the
English language was was imposed once
again through tremendous brutality on
the Filipinos who had by now become
Christians and who had forgotten their
Hindu past. Uh so that is what happened
and that's why uh the Philippines never
quite became a Spanishspeaking nation.
What happened to Latin America? Why did
Latin America become predominantly
Spanish- speaking apart from Brazil?
That's a different case. Why? Why is
that? First of all, because Latin
America underwent a massive genocide.
About 90% of the population of the
various parts of Latin America was wiped
out through various means either through
massacres, through forced genocide or
through smallpox and various other
illnesses that were introduced in the
native populations.
So approximately 90% of the native
populations were were decimated,
destroyed, wiped out, genocided by the
Spaniards, principally the Spaniards.
And then the Spaniards settled lots and
lots of European origin people in the
Americas in Latin America and that's why
Spanish became the principal language
that's spoken in the Latin Americas in
Latin America apart from Brazil where
you have Portuguese. So that's the
difference.
Right. Next question.
Nirvana Shanks says, "How did the
European colonization of native
populations near the modern day region
of Mexico, Mexico, affect the genetics
of the general populace of the present
time,
right? So like we discussed in the
previous question, uh the Spanish
colonization
of the Americas, Latin America begins uh
with the arrival of of of Christopher
Columbus in the Caribbean region. in
and eventually you know he and his
various other compatriates they take
over various parts of Latin America. uh
in 15 1521 you have the fall of the
noitan the fall of the Azak triple
alliance a empire at the hands of
Harbdan Cortes in the 1530s all the way
to the 1570s you have the destruction of
the inca empire by Franchesco Pzaro and
over time what happens is that about 90%
of the native population is
is eliminated through various means
either through violence or by smallpox
or other old world diseases or whatever
about 90% of the native population or
maybe more is killed. Genocide, total
genocide. Then
what you have is that you've got lots of
European origin people who settle in
these territories. So it was settler
colonization after genocide or during
genocide.
So because and then what you have is
that you have intermarriage
between the two populations between the
native populations who are uh at the in
in in in at the lower end of the cast
system that was imposed upon them and
and the occupiers the European occupiers
the Spanish occupiers who are the
privileged and the and the powerful ones
in the higher end of the power
differential. So if you look at the
Spanish I mean if you look at the uh
genetics of let's say Mexico and other
Latin American countries today you will
find that most people are what we call
mystizos which are mixed people mixed
race people and if you look at their
genetics overall about 50 60% of their
genetics between 45 to 55 45 to 60% of
the genetics will be native
and the rest so more than half the gen
more than 50% of the genetics are native
and the rest of it about 40% 45% or
whatever is European.
Now that's not all. There is nuance to
it. There are two kinds of
ancestries.
One is
the mitochondrial DNA ancestry.
Mitochondrial DNA is passed on from
mother to children.
So mother to children it's passed on but
male children cannot pass it on to their
descendants. only females can pass it on
to their descendants. So the mother will
pass on mitochondrial DNA to both male
as well as female offspring but only the
female offspring can pass it on to to
their offspring. That's how it is. So
that's why mitochondrial DNA is your
matrinal line of descent.
So if you look at the genetics of the
people in the in Latin America, if you
look at their mitochondrial DNA ancestry
about 90% of it is
native.
If you look at their patrinal DNA,
most of it
is European. What does it indicate? It
indicates that most of them are
descendants of children fathered by
Europeans with native women.
That is a classic symbol of colonization
and foreign occupation where the foreign
occupiers won and the local males were
wiped out and the women were
enlisted into the business of
procreation with the Europeans. That is
the deal. Right? So that is how um the
European occupation
of
Latin America and the devastation of the
native populations how that has
contributed to the kind of genetics that
you have in Latin America today. Clear
classic science of foreign occupation
you see in the tale that the DNA and and
genetics tells us. All right, next
question.
Amisha says, "If Brazil brought in way
more African slaves than the US or
Hayiti, why doesn't Brazil have a bigger
black or African origin population?"
Now, was forced racial mixing a big
reason for that?
Right? So, if you look at the number of
So, we had some there was something
called the transatlantic slave trade.
Let's look at the map. Let us look at
the map and understand what this
transatlantic slave trade was.
So here we have the map. Now we're going
to go to to the Atlantic region near the
equator. Okay? Not not the North
Atlantic, not the South Atlantic, but
the region near the equator. And it's
around this region around here that you
had the transatlantic slave trade. So
Africans were
captured in West Africa and they were
shipped across the Atlantic and they
were then sold in various parts of the
Americas whether it was the present day
United States or Brazil or other
territories. That's what happened. Now
the question is how many slaves did
these regions acquire from Africa? If
you look at the United States, it's, you
know, the official figures are less than
half a million slaves were shipped or
were received alive in the United States
over time. Half a million slaves,
African origin, black slaves in the US.
When it comes to Brazil, it's like 5
million plus. So Brazil got Brazil
acquired 10 time more than 10 times the
number of slaves the Americans the
United States present the United States
acquired. So Brazil brought brought in
like more than 10 times the number of
slaves African slaves than the US and
more than five times the number of
slaves that were brought into Hayi after
the destruction of uh the Dominican you
know the people who once lived in
Hispanola. the Karib the the the Karib
people
the the the Arawak people different
story um
so if that is the case why doesn't
Brazil have a much larger black
population today so here's the deal
less than official according to official
records less than half a million black
slaves were shipped to the United States
but those slaves were treated
you would say in a way that was not
going to kill them if it makes any
sense.
Look, the the slaves were treated as
goods. They were treated no different
from
livestock animals like like cattle or or
pigs or whatever. That's how slaves were
treated. They were not treated as human
beings by the Europeans. Utterly
barbaric practice, right? But when it
comes to the treatment of let's say
animals, there's different ways of
treating animals. If you treat them in a
certain way, they will thrive and they
will reproduce and they will they will
they will do well as long as you want to
keep them alive. But if you treat
animals poorly, animals die, right?
So in the United States, slaves were
given the kind of uh situ you know
living standards where they were treated
very harshly but they were not killed
and they were able to form families and
reproduce and and their population
actually increased over time. In Brazil
it was the other way around. The the
treatment was extremely harsh and the
mortality rate was very high. In the
United States, the mortality rate was
relatively much lower.
So in Brazil, you had extremely harsh
treatment of the African slaves. So
African slaves were brought in were
shipped to Brazil beginning in the
1500s, the first half of the 1500s, the
first half of the 16th century. And by
the 1800s, more than h more than 5
million African origin slaves were
shipped to Brazil. and they were put to
work in cotton plantations, sugar
plantations, sugar plantations. Uh then
uh diamond mines and other mines were
discovered. They were put to work in
those mines and the the treatment was
extremely harsh. The mortality was
extremely high. It was just brutal. It
was barbaric.
And u eventually by 1888 or somewhere
around that time, slavery was officially
abolished in Brazil.
But the slaves who are freed now they
were given
they were given no option to to survive.
So they were not given any kind of u
any kind of um remineration. They were
not given any any any any uh vocation.
They were not given any land that they
could work on. They were given no
compensation. So very quickly they found
themselves in situations that very much
mimicked slavery. Once again
and after 1888 or whichever year it was
that slavery was abolished, the
Brazilian government then began this
policy of encouraging large scale
European
settlement in Brazil to whiten the
population.
So being black was regarded as a stigma.
It was regarded as something very
inferior. And over time the populations
mixed. So the black people would event
would originally uh you know
procreate let's say or or have children
with the native people of Brazil and
eventually that got mixed with the white
populations also. So if you see the
official Brazilian statistics today I
would imagine that less than 10% of the
people of Brazil regard themselves as
black or or identify as black. So in
Brazil race how is race determined? Race
is determined by what the person decides
that their race is. So most people say
that we are not black. We are of mixed
ancestry or whatever but not black. And
that's why most people are regarded as
regarded as not black. But if you look
at the actual parentage and ancestry and
heritage of most of the Brazilian
people, at least half of them have
African ancestry. Right? So so that is
what happened.
Right?
Abisha says, "What was the slave
transportation process from Africa so
brutal when the slavers wanted to sell
healthy slaves to make profit in the
end?"
Okay. So once again, we are discussing
the transatlantic slave trade. Once
again, let's go to the map. Okay. So we
had the Europeans had this practice of
of capturing slaves in West Africa,
transporting them across the Atlantic
and selling them in places like Brazil,
in Latin America, in the United States
and so on. Now what was this process
like? So most of the slaves came from
Western Africa. Uh today in the US, one
of the biggest forms of music is the
blues. The blues. What is the roots of
the blues? The roots of the blues, blues
music is the music of Mali,
Western Africa music, Western African
music. So it was people mainly from the
western African region that were taken
as slaves across the Atlantic. So what
was the process like? Let's understand
what the process was like. So there
would be raiding parties sent into the
interior of West Africa and um helpless
people would be captured, men, women,
children. They would be chained up and
forced to march to the various trading
ports in West Africa. They would be
chained and kept there. They would be
kept there in in concentration camp
situations until the next ship would
come in. Then they would be crammed into
those ships in abysmal conditions.
Understand this my dear friends. These
slaves, African slaves were not regarded
as human beings by the Europeans.
They were regarded as goods. They were
regarded as cargo.
They were given the same treatment as
livestock animals. So, it has some
value, but it's not human. And it's it's
life doesn't matter. That's how they
would treat these people. They would
treat them as non-human.
So, these slaves would be chained and
they would be crammed into the holes of
ships
below deck. they would be crammed
together. Now, let me give you a rather
unfortunate way of understanding this or
visualizing this. Okay? Because the
Europeans regarded the Africans as the
same as animals, let me give you
an appropriate comparison. Okay? So, uh
if you to to understand the kind of
conditions these African these these
unfortunate African slaves were were
transported in. So if you see a pig farm
in China
and let's see images.
So if you see this, you see these pigs,
they actually are are living in decent
conditions.
This is not bad.
This is kind of bad. They're crammed
together.
This is decent.
This is bad.
The African slaves who were transported
were transported in conditions worse
than what you are seeing on the screen
right now.
This is good compared to what the
African slaves had to suffer. They had
to suffer conditions similar to these.
I I apologize for showing the way
animals are treated to make a
comparison, but that is the way the
Europeans treated the Africans.
That's exactly how the Europeans treated
the Africans. So they would be crammed
into the holes of ships below the decks.
There would be like several hundred of
them crammed into a small ship. There
would be no place to turn.
They would be in chains.
There would be no facilities as such to
to you know take care of physical
necessities. They would be given very
little water. They would be given
essentially rotten food, typically rice
or something like that. And uh
and the conditions would be really hot.
There would not be proper ventilation
because you're traveling near the
equator. So it would be hot in the
Atlantic. Very poor ventilation. When
there was a storm, they would get no
water at all. And typically the
mortality rate was would be I don't know
between 10% to 50% during a voyage.
So the qu the question is why was this
done in in this manner? Why was why were
so many people crammed into ships? So
many like animals because the traders
slave traders had this
ugly perverse
horrible logic. They were resigned to
the fact that 10 20% of their cargo will
die will perish. So if I'm transporting
100 and 20 will die, why not transport
120?
If I'm transporting 300
and 60 will die, why not transport 360
cram 60 more in there? That way even if
60 die, the rest will rest will reach.
So it was not about quality, it was
about quantity. As much as possible, as
many slaves as possible, let's cram them
into the into the hold of the ship and
how many however many of them survive,
we will sell them and make a profit.
That was the deal. The slavers never
wanted to sell healthy slaves. They
wanted to sell live slaves. It was
quantity, not quantity,
not quality that they were after. And
that's why that the process was so
incredibly inhuman and brutal. And today
they lecture us about human rights and
democracy and whatnot. Yeah. The same
people,
right? And Amisha once again many white
American slave owners fathered
illegitimate children with their slaves.
How many how were these mixed race child
slaves treated by their masters or
fathers?
So in the United States
once again you had slaves who would live
on on the property of rich white men.
And these rich white men
would have their own families. Obviously
they would have their wives. They the
they would have a wife, they would have
children. They would have a whole
household with multiple slaves who would
run the household. And you would have
slaves who would work on the farms and
whatnot. And many of the slaves were
women obviously, right? female African
slaves. And it was not uncommon for
these white masters to take multiple
female slaves as their sex slaves, as
their mistresses.
And when you do that, you're going to
father children with these unfortunate
ladies. Right? So many white American
slave owners did indeed father children
with their slaves. Now in our culture
there is no concept of illegitimacy.
There is no word for bastard in Sanskrit
right?
There is a word in Persian
but not in Sanskrit.
But in Christianity
you have the concept of bastardy
illegitimacy.
William the bastard who eventually
became William the conqueror 11 1066 AD
that's a different story. So many of
these
miserable, evil white slave owners
fathered unfortunate, illegitimate
children with their female with their
helpless female slaves.
So these slaves, these children that
were fathered obviously were half black,
half white. You could see that they were
different. They were not completely of
African origin. It was very clear and
many of them obviously would have some
of the facial features and
characteristics of the father.
Now when that happens it causes a
scandal.
The wife will be unhappy. Society will
see and then they will talk about you
behind your back. It'll cause a scandal.
So what do you do if you are the guy who
has done this? Well, you have multiple
options. One is you make the children
invisible. Uh don't bring them out in
public. Don't put them in positions
where they are public facing and just
treat them as slaves. Second, sell them
somewhere far away so that nobody will
see what you've done. And if a half
white, half black slave arrives in a on
a farm 200 km away, nobody will realize
what happened and who the father is.
That's the second option. The third
option is you actually give them some
some kind of benefits of of being your
child. So in some cases some of these
white uh these white masters would
sometimes you know give some kind of
unofficial education you know arrange
for some unofficial education for their
for their illegitimate children and when
they grow up they would either be given
privileged slave positions or they would
be freed by the father.
That was a minority of cases. In most
cases, they would be treated just as
slaves and the fathers do not care. They
would either be treated as slaves and be
brutalized just just like every other
slave or they would be sold off
somewhere else where the problem would
go away. So, one of the examples of
these prominent white slave owners was
the third president of the United States
of America, Thomas Jefferson.
He had this unfortunate
uh mistress who was an was an African
origin slave and he fathered multiple
children with her and uh he never
recognized the fact that those children
were his descendants
and uh yeah that was just the the deal.
So that is how um
these illegitimate children were treated
by their masters who also happened to be
their fathers. Right. Next question.
Once again, Amisha. So we're going to
talk about slavery today. [laughter]
Amisha says, "Were there white slaves in
the US?" Mid 1800s.
You had indentured servants who were
white.
For example, you would have uh people
who would come for from let's say
Ireland
who would be uh treated as indentured
servants. Now what's the difference
between slavery and indentured serv
servitude? Indentured servitude means
you would be a slave for a certain
number of years. So let's say you are a
poor Irishman and you are being
oppressed brutally by the British
occupiers of Ireland. You see today if
you look at the the map of the United
Kingdom, [clears throat]
you have multiple countries within the
United Kingdom. One is England.
The second is British occupied Wales.
The third is British occupied Scotland.
And the fourth is British occupied
Ireland, also known as Northern Ireland.
And there was a time when the British
occupied much of Ireland and brutalized
the people there.
So if you were a poor impoverished
Irishman
living under British occupation and you
wanted freedom from the godamned
British, from the accursed British, but
you had no means
to be free, then you would make a deal
with the devil. You will tell the guy
who has a ship and who is sailing to the
US, to the Americas, you would say,
"Sir, please allow me to to sell on your
ship. I have nothing to offer you but I
will serve you for x number of years
once I reach the US.
So then they would sign some kind of
agreement. The guy who doesn't know the
the the poor guy who is illiterate he
will sign an ex x on some document and
that's it. And he would be essentially a
slave for 10 years 15 years whatever the
number of years was and that was called
indentured servitude. It was technically
different from slavery, but but it was
almost the same thing as long as that
that contract was valid. And the Irish
were not regarded as whites, by the way.
The Irish were were racially
discriminated discriminated against. And
the way they became white was by
discriminating against the
African-Americans. That's a whole
different story. We'll not go there. So
you not you did not technically have
white slaves in the US, but you had
indentured servants and you had and you
had a cast system in the US. So the
people that mattered were the land
owners, the rich people. And if you were
a white person with no land or whatever,
then you were like almost the same in a
societal level as as a slave.
So technically you did not did not have
white slaves but for practical purposes
for all intents and matters it was very
similar to slavery especially for people
like the Irish maybe even the Germans
for a while.
So from various parts of Europe you
would you would have people who come in
people who did not speak English and all
they would be treated very poorly and
they would often end up uh in situations
and circumstances that kind of mimicked
slavery. So you did have that but
technically they were not slaves and
they even if they had no money and they
were almost on the same level as slaves
they still had rights and privileges
that the Africans did not have. First of
all they were regarded as human beings.
The Africans were not and other things
as well. So technically there was no
white slavery technically.
Krishna of the Surinamese Netherlands
says, "Can you give an can you give a
chronological timeline of the drying up
of the Saraspati river, the so-called
Gagar Hakra River today?"
Okay. So, let's go to the map. Can we
can we discover where this river is? The
Gagar Hakra River today.
Right. Okay. Let's go to the map and let
us go to northern India and let us
simply search for the Gagar Hakra River.
Gagar Hakra river and then you zoom in
there and there you find it. Gagar river
where is it? So today you have this
river
okay which is kind of a seasonal river
and it is fed from glacial melt waters
in the Himalayas
and this is all that remains of the once
mighty Sarasati and even today in the
rainy season in India the Gagar river
reverts to its monstrous stra state to
its majestic state and it floods
and uh yeah it it once again for some
time becomes the mother of floods. So
the Gagar hakra river is all that is
left today of the great once great
saraspati. What is the chronological
timeline of the drying up of this great
river? So about 10,000 years ago this
was a major massive river. If you look
at the paleo channel the dried riverbed
in some places it is several kilometers
wide. It is which was a massive river.
It was a perennial river. It was a it
was a glacial meltwater
fed river and also mon monsoonfed river.
In those days 10,000 years ago the the
Indian rainy season was way heavier than
what it is today. So you had very heavy
rainfall in the rainy season that would
totally like transform the river into a
beast. And even when it was not raining,
it was felt it was fed by the melting
slows snows and melting glaciers in
northern India in the Himalayas and and
in the Himalayan foothills. So it is a
very major river and how was the river
fed? It did not directly emanate from
the Han Himalayas. uh to some extent it
did it did but you also had rivers like
uh the Yamuna and the Sautl that drained
into the Sarasati that that served as
tributaries of the Saraswati and that's
how the Saraswati was so massive and
such a major river and the mother of
Indian civilization to a very large
extent
so that's the deal with Daraswati
okay now what happened is that around
6,000 BC See
around that time multiple events
happened. Firstly, there was a major
tectonic event in northern India. A
tectonic event means an earthquake,
major earthquake or a series of major
earthquakes. And what
effect this had is that it diverted the
course of the satlage in the Yamuna and
now the Saraspati no longer received the
waters of these two rivers and that was
a major issue. Secondly, around 6,000 BC
which is around 8,000 years before
today, there was a slow gradual
monotonic decline in the volume
of the Indian monsoon of the Indian
rainy season. So very slow very gradual
decline in the amount of rainfall that
you get every year in the subcontinent.
Because of that from about 8,000 years
before before today the Sarasi slowly
started declining declining declining.
It was imperceptible. Nobody could
really see it happening in real time. It
happened over several thousand years.
But
so the Sarasati is still a major river
during the so-called mature harpan phase
which is about 5,000 years before today.
That's when you have the peak of the
Saraspati synindu phase of our history
where this it's a fully industrialized
urbanized phase of Indian history right
and this was all centered around the
STANu region and the major river there
was the Sarasati and you have thousands
of archaeological sites that are present
today
on the along the dry riverbed of the
Sarasmati
then the river starts declining
obviously the decline becomes quite
visible and by about 1800 or 1700 BC the
river significantly dries out and at
least in the southern half of its course
it's dry and it it drains out into a big
lake in the present day Rajasthan region
and that lake also eventually dries out
and becomes the Tar desert
and today all you have left is the
seasonal Gagar Hakra river
so that is kind of of a chronological
timeline of the drying up of the
Sarasotai River. And once the river
started drying out in a significant way,
all the great cities and settlements
that had been built on the banks of this
great river, they had to disperse
because without the river, without
without the without the water that the
rivers gives you, the river gives you,
you can't have a civilization. So
Indians then had to disperse from this
region and go either eastwards or
westwards. So the the ones who went
westwards
went on to to form the Mitani kingdom
and the Hittite kingdom and so on and
the ones who went eastwards went and
settled in various parts of India
interior parts of India like the Ganga
Yamuna plains and all that and they
formed the great Mahajanapadas and so
on. That is how it happened and that is
essentially the the an overview of the
timeline of the drying up of the great
Sarati river.
And because the rainfall or or the
decline in rainfall caused the the loss
of this great river for us, it had
profound effects on the way we worship
gods.
During the Vic days, the Vic period of
forestry,
we had a pantheon of gods that still
exists, but it's no longer worshiped the
way it was in the past. The greatest of
the gods of the Vic pantheon was Indra,
the great storm god, thunder god.
His major weapon was the vajgerra, which
has two meanings. The vajger is a
hammer. It's also a thunderbolt, right?
And Indra obviously is also the god of
the reigns. And because Indra failed to
provide the reigns which ended up
killing the Saraswati,
I suppose we stopped worshiping Indra.
You understand?
So all of this ties in ties up together,
right? Next question.
Feline lover. That's quite a name.
Feline lover. Which kind of felines?
Cats, tigers, saber-tooths. Okay. Fan
lover says wheel imprints found in
cintashta are considered to be an
evidence of the existence of a chariot
and cintashta is credited for the
invention of chariots despite no actual
chariot ever being found in the time
period it's claimed okay but an actual
chariot has been discovered in sonali
and it's considered it's portrayed by
the westerners and various Indian
colonized morons as a bullet bulock
card. Why is there so much intellectual
dishonesty? What's my opinion? Okay,
first of all, what is the sintta thing,
right? So, the cinta culture is a
culture that has been discovered in
essentially in central Asia. Let's let's
Google it. Um, it's been discovered in
Central Asia
and it is, you know, by the Arian
invasion migration theory folks, it is
considered to be the uh original
homeland of the Indo-Iranians. Oh,
Saintta
culture. Let's look at the map what
we're talking about. We're talking about
this part of the world. So, it is
central Asia and almost like Eastern
Europe to some extent. That is it's not
it's obviously not very far from India.
And if you look at uh the kind of uh
archaeological findings there that you
find,
it's clear that the culture is kind of
similar
to the ancient Indo-Iranian culture.
Now you have these burials there. Okay,
burials. And in the burials they have
discovered the imprints of wheels.
So they haven't discovered wheels. They
haven't discovered chariots. They've
discovered imprints of wheels and and
and pigments left behind by wheels. And
they have interpreted that as the
evidence of the presence of chariots.
They said that you have two wheel. So
these are two wheeled chariots they're
talking about. So they said that they
found imprints of two wheels, you know,
lined up together and in those graves
they also find horse sacrifices. So that
obviously sounds very much like uh
something the Arians would do. Us our
people, us and the Iranians, we would
our ancestors sacrificed horses
deal with it. We did. So, so we have
horse sacrifices in these burials. We
also have wheels that seem to you we
also have imprints of wheels that have
been interpreted as the evidence of
chariots and various other artifacts
that once again are claimed to tie up
and the whole package. It it it
allegedly says that there there were
chariots that were being used by the
Sintashtra people there. Okay. So based
on this circumstantial
fragmentaryary evidence they said that
the sashta culture was the originator
was the discoverer and the pioneer of
chariot warfare.
Now what have we discovered in Sawali?
Sonali chariot obviously right?
Sawali chariot.
Sonali chariot. Sawali chariot. So
what's this chariot look like? So this
is what it looks like in in in the
museum. This is how it was discovered.
Obviously you have horses and you have
the chariot u and the chariot is made of
copper. Right now if you look at the
chariot copper tubes
uh where do okay look at this look at
the schematic. It's not quite a
schematic but it's it kind of like an
x-ray of what we what we have discovered
there. This is what it looks like. So
inside the Senoli chariot you had this
copper tubes. The copper was like 99%
pure copper. Okay?
Almost like super pure copper and you
had the entire chassis. The chassis of
the chariot was made of copper tubing.
Now why on earth did these folks, our
ancestors make a chariot out of copper
tubing?
The chassis. Okay. So, let's look at
this car chassis.
Tubes.
Check this out. You see this? Modern day
car chassis are made of tubes of various
kinds of metals. Maybe it's no longer
copper, but it's all tubes. Why tubes?
Because you don't have any corners. You
don't have any right angles.
So it is something that PE that
engineers still use today in modernday
cars,
metal tubes and the Sali chariot had
copper tubes
essentially ultra pure copper 99% pure
copper tubes.
What does pure copper look like? Pure
copper roofs. [snorts] What's it look
like? Check this out. This is what it
look like. This was the color of those
tubes.
So the chariot glowed like this
and it was extremely advanced
technology.
This was a very strong, hardy, tough
chariot. It was not a wooden chariot.
Right now, why would you make a bullock
cart
and design it like like like a Formula 1
car? Please explain to me.
whatever 2 4,000 years ago or whenever
it was 3 and a half thousand years ago.
Why would you
construct a bulock car with the design
of a Formula 1 car with with extreme
engineering and ultra pure copper? Why
copper tubes and stuff? Why would you do
that?
Why would farmers use pure copper
instead of wood for bulock cuts? Please
explain. M so clearly this is utter
intellectual dishonesty and the folks
who are behind this are the ones who are
the proponents of the Arian invasion
migration tourism picnic theory and they
want to say India did not create
anything of any value it was all brought
in from outside it is to keep Indians
colonized mentally and lots of Indians
participate in this and they make fun of
the findings oh it was a chariot it's a
it was not a chari it's a bulock car
Indians are are their own worst enemies
my Simple question to you all is why
would you construct a bulock car with
the engineering technology of a Formula
1 car? Answer that
race car. A race car
right
Singh says the term Arian please explain
its origins. Why it became Arian when it
was originally Arya? Why were the Nazis
so obsessed with this term and why did
they corrupt it in Western Hemisphere?
And why is it that even today when they
the why is it that they equate the
swastik symbol as something negative
even today and shub says the Sanskrit
word Arya refers to a person with a
dharmic code of conduct. How was it
anglicized to aran to become a racial
term also why are Persians considered
arians when they left the dharmic code
of conduct? Okay, what does the term
arda mean? The original term arya it's a
sanskrit term it means someone who is
noble not by blood by but but by by
comportment by behavior
by lifestyle you you have a noble
lifestyle lifestyle your behavior is
that of a noble person it was not a
racial term it was a term of of
civilizational refinement
okay a superior person by behavior
that's what it meant so
that is the original term, the original
meaning of the term Arya. It was never
Aryan, it was Arya. Then the Persians
who are our own people, they migrated
westwards. They the parro people and
they founded what is now Persia and they
started using the term Arya as a as an
ethnic self as a designator.
So they started using the term as the
name of their ethnicity.
So it for them it no longer meant noble
it meant us the people the para people
we are we are the Arya people that's
what they started using the term as so
the original term was the Sanskrit term
Arya and then the Persians started using
that as the name of their ethnicity so
the only two peoples who have the right
to call themselves Arya are the Indians
and the Persians
no one else. Okay. Now what happens is
that um is that the um the Europeans
when they start
when they rediscovered India
rediscovered India with the Vasco
Dagamar 1498 uh when they started coming
to India and discovering India and
interacting with Indians and learning
India India's culture languages they
started suddenly seeing these weird
similarities between Indian languages
and European languages.
striking shocking similarities between
Sanskrit and Greek and Latin
and I'll not go into the details because
they are very obvious. So it was very
clear these languages are clearly
related to each other. The words for ma,
pitha, braha,
so many words
essentially the same in these languages.
And which is the oldest of the
languages? Is it Greek? Is it Latin? Is
it Sitrit? It's clearly Sanskrit.
Right? And Persian, Persian language,
the old Persian language was like an
upper branch of version of Sanskrit. So
there was that also. Right? So all of
this fit together and and then the
Europeans discovered the term Arya.
now. And then Max Miller brought in his
Arian invasion theory and he
force-feeded everything into the
4,000year time span of the Christian
calendar or whatever it is, the creation
of the the universe by by Yahweh and all
that. And that is the beginning of the
misrepresentation of Indian history and
the beginning of the Arian invasion,
migration, tourism, picnic myth.
Now the Germans their nation is an
artificial nation created in 1871 by
Ottoan Bismar
and the Germans suffered humiliation in
the in the first world war and uh there
was this tremendous sense of you know we
need to do something something about
this and that gave rise to the u the
national socialist party Nazi party and
uh Adolf Hitler. So the Nazis,
they sought to revive Germany. They
sought to make Germany great again.
Okay? Make Germany great again. M GGA.
That's what they wanted to do. And they
wanted something to rally the people
around. So their idea was that the
Germans are the supreme race in the
world. The sup the uberbench,
the superior man, the master race. that
the Germans and the Nordic people, the
the northern European people are the
superior master race and
and in the 19th century because they had
discovered the Europeans that there are
similarities between the Indians between
Sanskrit and these old languages they
also discovered the term Arya. So they
started using the term not Arya but
Aryan for all the Indo-Uropean peoples
who probably obviously had descended
from a common group if you look at the
linguistic evidence and because the
Europeans were the dominant race in the
world at that time because they
colonized most of the world they decided
that the origin of the Indo-Uropean
people was in Europe not in India even
though Sanskrit is the oldest language
and so on. So they started this this
revis this revisionism of history which
is now the mainstream history and if you
go against that we are revisionists
today. They started the revisionism of
history. So they completely distorted
history and they claimed that the
Europeans are the master race the
original arians and the Germans just
took it forward. So the Germans wanted
this term for themselves Arian because
it gave them the prestige of the
association with these two ancient
civilizations India and Persia.
So they they misappropriated this term
arian and once again the sus the swastik
symbol which obviously originates in
India and it has a very positive
auspicious connotation and it's found
essentially on every almost on every
continent.
Now this symbol was also found in
Europe. It was a symbol of of
auspiciousness. If you look at uh the
Finland air force [laughter] let's look
at that shall we? Okay. Uh Finland Air
Force
swastika.
So the Finland Air Force
it used to have this marking and this
was not Nazi.
The swastika was found all across the
world. It was always regarded as a
symbol of auspiciousness and it is also
a symbol that originates in India. It is
associated with Arya culture. So they
the Nazis appropriated and stole the
swastika also. Now the old German flag
had three colors red, black and white.
Okay, old German flag. Let's see.
Old German Empire flag.
What's it look like?
This was the set of colors.
Red, black, and white. So Hitler took
the swastika, he twisted it around, gave
it those colors and made it look like
something similar to the communist
hammer and sickle. Okay, communist
hammer and sickle. Check this out.
Something similar to this, right? So it
became a direct competitor to the
communist hammer and sickle. the Naz the
Nazi ugly evil version distortion of the
swastikov the hakenroits
so that's the origin of all these
distortions misappropriations and today
the word Arian is regarded as a as a
white supremacist word which is so wrong
we are the Arya people we and the
Persians are the Arya people nobody else
the Europeans aren't Arya they are
unaria by the a an Arya. Now, Shub says
Arya means a person with a dharmic code
of conduct, a noble code of conduct. So,
that's how it was anglicized to Arian
etc. But why are the Persians considered
Arians when they left the Dharmic code
of conduct? Yeah. During after the reign
of Kurush, Cyrus the Great, they adopted
uh the the the religion or you know the
the the ver the religious version of
Zaratustra which kind of inverted
Hinduism which was a rebellion against
Hinduism and it no longer followed the
Vic ways of life.
Before Zaratostra the Persians followed
the Vic ways of life but Zorostanism
brought in a different way of life which
was nonvedic which was essentially a
rebellion against the Vic ways of life.
So if they left if the Persians left the
dharmic code of conduct how can we call
them the arya
because they chose to call themselves
area even though they had left the
dharmic code of conduct. Now if we
insist that only people who have the
dharmic code of conduct can be called
the aras then 99 people person of people
in India can't be called ar today
because 99% of Indians maybe more no
longer follow the vic way of life. So
let's not be [laughter]
overly judgmental.
Um
Abdai Gardes Abdes say love says love
from Afghanistan. Thank you sir. love
from bat. Before Islam in Kabul was
Hinduism bulk in Bkhara you had
Buddhism. Now my question is which
religion did the pashons have? For
example, we have a pashon tribe called
the Mongal tribe. Hope you find I hope
you find more.
A great question. What was the original
religion of the Pashtun people? Who are
the Pashtun people? Who are the true
Afghans?
There are various ways of looking at
Afghanistan. Historically like you are
correctly saying
historically Afghanistan
was called Gandhar. The whole region was
called Gandhar. Later on it was called
Kurasan.
Various words for it but the original
name of the region was Gandhar and the
people who lived there were Indians
and their descendants are the Pashons.
That is what I can say in British but
we'll look into this in more detail
obviously. So you have a pashon clan
called the Mongal clan. You have so many
names in Afghanistan which are descended
from Indian names right. Um if you look
at the pashon culture if you look at
pashtunali the code of conduct of the
pashons it is essentially if you remove
the religious elements the Islamic
elements from it it is nothing but the
code of conduct of the rajbuts.
It's the same thing. If someone comes to
your house as a guest
and asks for your protection, then you
have to if required give your life to
protect the person. That is the Rajput
code of conduct. It's also the Pashtun
code of conduct, isn't it? Um, now let's
look at see there's there's very little
um
there's very little
hard research, academic research that's
that's been done. One thing I can tell
you, I don't have the the the the
evidence right now, but I've shown that
in past episodes a long time ago, the
Pashon DNA, if you look at that, the
Pashons are
essentially an extension of the North
Indian population genetically. Now,
today, if you look at Afghanistan's
genetics, there's so many genetics that
are non-Indian in there. You have so
many ethnic groups that are not Indian,
not of Indian origin, of Turk origin.
The Tajiks are not Turk. They are
Indo-Iranian. That's different. But the
Turkmans,
the Usuzbcks, the Khazaras, these are
all non-Indian. And those genetics have
introgressed into Afghanistan and and
even in entered the Pashon lineages. So
if we do Pashon genetics today, it's
going to be a mixed bag. But if you did
Pashon genetics a thousand years ago, it
was all Indian. Now let's look at this
uh uh this research paper by uh aan
historian.
[clears throat]
So it's by a gentleman called Arif
Akunzada on pashons and pashto in Gadar
with a brief essay on pashon aan
ethnogenesis. Now let's look at the
actual PDF right. Uh so this is the PDF
and according to him pashto is primarily
a saka or skithian language. Okay, as
you say if you say so it's in my opinion
more of a dardic language. Uh it has
deep languages with existing dialects in
the primary language groups such as
yikda mji speaking spoken in north chall
and to its west it has a close cognatic
Persian ancient holy language of a
western okay uh all of that etc.
Gandhar. The Sakas ruled in Gandhar for
a decade or two. Their influence is
negligible except for the coins of their
four Hindu kings. [snorts]
All of that.
Besides Iranian roots and legacies,
Pashto also owes a great deal in
formative acquisitions and
characteristics to the local Indicarit
local Indicarit in ancient Dardic
dialects. The formers being the
predecessors of current living languages
such as Hindu, Punjabi and Saraki.
Um
we have to identify which ethnicities
occupied and controlled Gandhar
especially during the last 1500 years
after the fall of imperial Porsche to
Iran to Islam of which it was a key
province. The name Gandhar has
disappeared off of the radar about
thousand years ago after the we know
that yeah with the arrival of Mahmud of
Ghazni. Its ancient ethnic composition
remained relatively undisturbed for the
next 500 years after him until the
advent of the muggles in 1526 and they
messed up the genetics
after that. So the most ancient
population of Afghanistan was Indic or
Hinduki which spoke Prakit dialects now
known as Hindo in Punjabi and then you
have Cyrus of Persia and so on. Um and
you have the Paktas the Paktans
the Paktas of the Herodotus and the
Rigida respectively people who were to
later give a skitian language the name
of Pakto and so on. So you can check
this out. This goes into significant
detail. They talk about the Skitians uh
and the Pashtun of Ghana ethnicity. It
arose it arose long after 1526 with the
muggal muggal empire. Uh the paktas were
mentioned in the rigida also by the by
hiodotus
and so on. Um the name of the major and
dominant Afghan tribal division the
Sarabani is believed to have a Rajput
origin from Suryaban or Suryabanchi.
Suryanchi. So the Sarabani Afghan tribe
or clan is a Suryawanchi tribe and the
legend of their alleged Jewish origins
is it's a it's it's it's a myth. Okay,
it's a myth that has been introduced
into Afghanistan at a much later date
and so on. So it's a long story. Uh and
and that is the deal about Afghanistan
and the origins of the Pashtos. The
Pashtos were originally
warrior clans of India. Some of them
were royal lineages. Suryanches.
Okay. And over time they have been
Islamized obviously in the past 1,000
years. Uh especially those who were
Buddhists they Islamized on the drop of
a hat. The remaining ones they they
resisted as long as they could even
until the 20th century even the
beginning of the 21st century you had
significant Hindu and sick population in
in Gandhar Afghanistan and uh today it's
not quite the case so much so like I
said the historical name of the region
was Gandhar later during the because of
Persian and Turk influences mainly
Persian influences the region was called
Kurasan. Now what does cororasan mean?
What does korchid mean? There's this
Persian name calledid, right? The word
kurid.
Kurshid
comes from swaret.
Swar means the sun. Ket means shining.
Kurshid means shining sun. If you ask a
pari person or Persian person, what does
the word kurchid mean? They'll say it
means the sun. You can Google it and
check it out. You can fact check what
I'm saying. What does koshided mean?
Let's see. Let's see right now. Meaning
of the name Kushid. Okay.
Of the name Korchid,
it means sun or radiant sun.
Okay. Swarak.
It's not Persian. It is before Persian.
It was Sanskrit. Saraka
Swaraketa became Korashid. What is the
origin of Korasan?
Sarasthan.
Sarasthan the land of the sun. Very
similar to Sarashtra.
Saurashtra solar land. Solar
kingdom.
Kurasan was Sarasthan. The land of the
sun. The the eastern land. The land
where the sun rose.
That's what Korasan meant. It had the
same name as Sarashtra which is for the
south. So that's these are the ancient
connections between Bharatwash and
Gandhar of which Gandhar was obviously a
part of Bhatwash. And the Pons well they
are our own people. Actually speaking
even today the Pashons aren't like
foreigners.
Our culture our way of life our
everything is very similar. You meet a
person, that person will never feel like
a foreigner to you if you're Indian. You
won't feel like it's a foreigner you're
dealing with. You understand each other
immediately. Yeah. Because deeper down
you have the same cultural origins.
So that's the deal with the pons.
Okay. Um
Girish Kumar and Shub was the Kushan
Empire Indian or foreigner? a foreigner
then why the Koshans are praised and
muggles are believed to be foreign
invaders some people argue that Koshans
were Indianized it doesn't make them
Indian what's my opinion
look
so apparently Akbar is an Indian but
Kaneshka is not Indian apparently look
uh the Kushans obviously they came from
um the Tarim River basin region which is
present day northern Singang
currently occupied by China
now the Kushans their ancestors were the
Tokarian Tara people or Tushara people
whose mummies are still fine in the
region and the Kushans they invaded
India because they were fleeing from the
Huns the Shaoo and um
they displaced the Indo- Greek the Yanas
and they took over northern India
eventually much of India and the
greatest emperor was Peshka. Now what
are the contributions of the Kushans to
India? H what are the contributions?
First of all, they made India immensely,
immensely rich, wealthy by controlling
all the trade in Asia between east and
west. They the Koshan Empire occupied
much of central Asia from the shores of
the Aral Sea to the Caspian Sea all the
way to Shinjang and all the way into
northern and western India. The western
coast of India including Sarah where you
have ports that go all the way to that
were trading with Rome. So all the trade
between India and Europe essentially
Roman Empire was controlled by the
Kushans and that made India immensely
wealthy. The Kushans also traded with
China and also taxed Chinese trade
whatever which whatever happened to
whatever extent between China and
Europe. So once again that made India
super wealthy. The Kushans were sun
worshippers
and also they worshiped all other gods.
You can imagine super polytheists. Um
and it is alleged my dear friends that
emperor Kaneshka was a Buddhist great
pattern of Buddhism and the Kushans were
great Buddhist patrons right
let's fact check that okay
let's see this what percentage
of
Pushan coinage P features
Buddhist imagery/
slash symbolology/theddha.
Let's see what the answer is. Well under
1%.
Buddhist imagery appears on less well
under 1% of all known Kushan coins.
The vast majority has a vast diverse
pantheon of Greek, Iranian and Hindu
deities. Okay, forget about Kushan
coinage. Let's say Kaneska.
Kaneshka's coinage.
Let's see once again same question.
Buddhist imagery on Kaneshka's coinage
is extremely rare featuring on well
under 1% of all coins in issued by him.
His coins had Shiva. They had various
Iranian gods. They their Zoroastrian
motives. They had Greek gods because of
the Greek you know Indo- Greek regency
he he had conquered. Lots of Indian
deities le well under 1% of the coins
have Buddha but his portrait is a
Buddhist king your historians are a set
of inveterate liars your Indian
historians liars all of them
okay so the Kushans
they Indianized completely they
assimilated completely into the Indian
Indian population completely without
friction whatsoever
They are culturally Indian anyway.
They may have looked somewhat different
initially after a couple of generations
even that was gone.
And they they strengthened fortified
India's military. They brought in new
tactics in and strategies into India's
military. standing armies, cavalry, you
know, big focus on the cavalry and um
they under Kushan rule so much culture,
new culture, you know, there was this
great eflloresence of culture. You had
the Gandhara school of arts, you had the
Matura School of Art, very different
schools of art and beautiful art and so
much more. And the Kushans did more than
anyone I can think of to spread India's
culture far and wide. the spread Indian
culture into China all the way to
Southeast Asia all the way to Japan
Hinduism and also some some Buddhism but
today it's all Buddhism Buddhism they
talk about right
so they
they furthered the Indian national
interest they took care of India's
national security civilizational
security they to they they they enhanced
India's economy significantly and they
spread India's culture far and wide but
they are still foreigners
but Akar
is Indian. So I mean
what logic do we have there? Right? It
doesn't make any sense.
Okay.
Me says how did the Hikos period change
Egyptian military organization and
foreign policy? The Hicks period.
So
Egypt around 1800 BC around that time
maybe 1700 BC probably somewhere around
1800 BC was gradually invaded by a bunch
of people who came from God knows where
who came from from
what is present in the region of Israel.
Let's once again go to the maps. Okay
maps
and let's see where is Egypt and where
is Israel today. So we have Egypt here.
We know where Cairo is in the in the
pyramids. Now if you go to the northeast
of that you have the Sai region and
beyond that you have Egypt, labor and
all of that and north of that you have
Syria and Anatolia which is present day
currently occupied by Turkey.
So the Hikos people they came from this
region Syria, Lebanon, Israel, that
region and they gradually encroached
into Egypt and eventually conquered
Egypt and they ruled Egypt for about a
century century and a half. So initially
they they made some small settlements in
the Egypt region and uh and the
Egyptians uh they were the Egyptian
kingdom was not very powerful at that
time. Egypt had a very isolationist
policy. Egypt only focused on national
defense. Just like India today, today
India's military is all about defense,
defense, defense.
You don't hit sixes, you just block the
ball. Right? That's that's India's
military policy for the since 1947. Keep
defending. Keep defending. Keep
defending.
Until the 1990s, India was completely
isolated just like North Korea. Indians
had no idea what was happening outside.
Egypt at this time was just like that.
completely isolated from the world and a
completely defensive policy. Because of
that, the Hixos came in and encroached
into Egypt and settled settled down and
they set up cities and all that.
Eventually, one of the Hixos kings,
he sent a letter to the Egyptian king
whose capital city was like 100
kilometers away. And the Hixos king
whose capital, so the two capitals, the
two cities are about 100 or so
kilometers away from each other. The
Hixos king sends a letter to to the king
of Egypt saying that you have a big pool
with hippopotamuses in your city and the
splashing of the hippopotamuses in your
city
is preventing me from sleeping.
So do something about it. It was an
insult obviously. Right? So the Egyptian
king instead of taking that action, he
went with his army and marched on the
Hixos uh territory and there was a
battle.
What was the name of the Egyptian king?
Last let's Google that. Yeah, let's
let's Google this.
Uh last Egyptian king, last Egyptian
king before Hicks period. What was his
name? His name was Senetto. Let's take a
look at what this gentleman looks like.
Mommy.
Uh, trigger warning, not pretty.
It's Let's take a look at his mommy.
See, it's going to say that. Uh, why is
this blanked out? Turn safe search off.
All right, there we have it.
That's what his mummy looks like.
So he went to battle against the Hicks
and uh this is what happened to him. As
you can see the instruments that were
used were battle axes.
So the Hicks
they brought in new technology into
Egypt. What are the technologies the
Hixos brought in into Egypt that the
Egyptians did not have? First of all the
Hixos brought in war chariots. Two
wheeled chariots.
What kind of chariot? Chariot drawn by
horses. And the chariot would have two
people.
One was the person
driving the chariot. The other was the
warrior.
So you would have a sarati and you would
have a Maharati.
What will what weapons did the Maharati
use? He used a composite bow. Not a
standard bow. A composite bow. What does
a composite bow look like? Let me show
you what a composite bow looks like.
Lord Rama bow. What does a composite bow
look like? This is what a composite bow
looks like.
Okay. This is the shape of a composite
bow. This is the shape of a composite
bow. The Hixos brought in the composite
bow. They brought in the rata. They
brought in the sarati. They brought in
the Maharati. The Maharati would have a
composite bow. He would also have a
spear.
Another weapon that Vixos brought in was
the Parasu, which is the battle axe made
of copper.
Um, what was the Hixos religion? Their
main god was a thunder god and a storm
god. Today's European and historians
will identify him with the Semitic god
Bal.
The Hixos also, is that true? Not sure
about that. Uh, is that correct? I'm not
sure about that. The Hixos also
performed horse sacrifices.
The Hixos came from the region where you
would eventually have the Mitani and
Hittite empires. The Mitani and
Hitittite empires were ruled by people
who spoke Sanskrit, by the way. Anyway,
these are all circumstantial
connections. The Europeans will say that
the Hixos were seatic people.
So the Hixos came in, they defeated the
Egyptians and they ruled Egypt for about
150 years. Eventually the Egyptians were
able to take over again and you had the
new kingdom of Egypt which was the
greatest glorious period of Egyptian
history ever. You had uh Akraten, you
have Hutch, the female pharaoh, you had
Tutenham and so on. The greatest most
glorious period of Egyptian history. And
if you look at their historical records
that they wrote from the time, they
speak very bitterly of the Hixos
occupation. They speak about the century
of humiliation.
And after the Hicks were defeated,
Egypt, which formerly had this
isolationist foreign policy, suddenly
became an expansionist kingdom. And they
used the memory of the century of
humiliation to justify their
expansionism. Reminds us of does it
remind you of China?
I keep saying to you all history is
cyclical. History occurs in cycles.
Well, there you have it. So, that's kind
of how it was. Okay.
And yeah, it also changed Egypt Egypt's
military organization. The Egyptian new
kingdom adopted all of the technology,
all of the tactics, all of the
strategies, all of the organization,
everything that the Hixos brought in and
that made them a formidable power in
West Asia. Right. Okay.
really now says can you tell us about
the Japanese cast system also why aren't
scholars around the world researching on
this like they do for the Indian one
the Japanese cast system um
so look any functioning society
it's been around for a long time and
it's advanced it's going to have
division of labor it's going to have
social stratification it's going to have
various
various ious social groups, so various
casts.
So the so the Japanese society before
the major coup, the major restoration,
it had
four major divisions in society.
[laughter]
Four major divisions in society. That
reminds you of the Chinese system. Okay.
China for occup
China China
for occupations.
What was the Chinese for occupations?
The Chinese had a four four tiered cast
system, four categories of the people.
You had the warrior nobles, the
chhatrias. Then you had the nong, the
peasant farmers. Then you had the
artisans and craftsmen. And you had the
merchants and traders. And you also had
other you know
straight off society that you don't
mention here. And this is similar to the
Japanese system the shino kosho
Japanese shinino kosho system which once
again had four major divisions of
society. You had the samurai at the very
top. The samurai were the chhatrias of
Japan. And then you had the the the the
you had the farmers and you had the
artisans and you had the merchants and
so on. You had four divisions of society
in in Japanese society and civilization.
But you also had a diff another level of
society which was the outcasts.
The eeta and the hinn the were called
the great filth and the hinnan were
called the non-persons, non-humans.
And today these people collectively are
called the burakumin. So the ita were
people who were engaged in very
degrading professions like uh like like
like
butchery of animals, slaughtering of
animals, skinning of animals. So you see
Japanese culture
for about 2,000 years has regarded
killing animals as as sinful. It is
sinful not just in the dharmic sense,
Hindu Buddhist sense, but also in the
Shinto culture.
The Shinto and Dharmic culture are very
similar. So killing animals was was ill,
right? That's how it was. And Japan was
a vegetarian society for about a
thousand years. They used to eat fish,
but they would not kill animals. And the
Maji coup, the Maji restoration forced
Japanese people to start eating beef,
right? And that led to revolts and and
and a lot of strife in society. It was
believed that because the the emperor
had set the example by eating beef. It
was believed by a lot of people in Japan
that the gods would now desert Japan and
a big catastrophe will come up upon
Japan. Kind of happened, didn't it?
Eventually. Yeah. Anyhow, so um in
Japan, you had these two two outcast
groups, the ETA and the Hin. And u the
ETA were the people who would do
slaughtering of animals and and and
skinning of animals. Uh they would also
uh serve as executioners who would
execute human beings who people were
sentenced to death. And the Hen
[clears throat] also did certain other
um other other functions of society that
were regarded as uh not desirable or or
you know that sort of thing. So these
people today are called the burakumin
and they kind of still are to a certain
extent discriminated against allegedly
in Japanese society. You know most
people want will not want their
daughters to marry a person from that
group. The people who belong to the
burakumin category many of them are part
of the yakuza which is the Japanese
mafia that sort of thing and so on. So
that's about the Japanese car system but
it's not something that's limited to
Japan. You have the same sort of thing
in China as well. You have the same sort
of thing in Europe. In France, you had a
a social group, an ethnic group or
whatever it was called the Kagago. C A
G- O Ts Kag. Let's Google that as well.
Why not? Since we are doing this. Okay.
Um where is Google?
Okay. Let's Google this. C A G O Ts Kag.
So the Kag were a persecuted minority
group in western France and Northern
Spain who were treated abysmally. They
were treated horribly. Uh they were not
allowed to use the same water as the
regular people. They were not allowed to
enter churches from the same door and uh
they would be killed if they married
married a regular person and so much
more terrible discrimination. We and no
one knows what is the origin of this.
You also had the gong farmers in England
who were treated like outcasts and also
in France and so many more examples in
various parts of the world where you
have these social groups that are
regarded as well you know outcasts or
untouchables or whatever. You have this
all across the world. uh and why do
scholars not do this? Because this the
the that is reserved for Hindus, right?
Only India is supposed to be vilified
for the so-called cast system. Even
though we do not have a cast system, we
had a vernati system which is different
from a four-tier cast system. Four-year
cast system was imposed upon India by
the British. And it's been it's been now
enforced and made into a reality by the
government of India today.
Right? Today cast is everything. You get
resolutions based on casts. In China,
everybody wants to become as advanced as
possible. In India, everyone wants a
backward cast status. Everyone is trying
to go backwards in India. Uh so this is
the difference between India and China.
But anyhow, that's the deal about the
cast system. Every country has it. Every
culture has had it. It's it's not like
it's something that only India has uh
seen.
Okay. Um
Girish Kumar says, "Was the Marata
Empire a panindia empire or just a
regional power in Dean?" Was the Marata
Empire just a small regional power in
Dean? Let us answer this question by
looking at the map. Okay. Uh high tide
of Marata Empire.
Marata Empire. Let's take a look at the
image. So a picture will tell you a
million words. Right?
In 1759 AD this was the Marata Empire.
Here's a different way of looking at it.
Right? 1705
you have the Muggal Empire. 1759 look at
what happened. The Maratas have gone all
the way into Gandhar parts of
Afghanistan.
As you can see this is a gigantic
empire. India [snorts] is not the small
small piece of land. It's a
subcontinent. The Marata Empire was
vast.
Certainly larger than the Sat Vahana
Empire. certainly certainly larger than
than various than the Sikh empire for
example right which came later obviously
so the Marata empire was vast it was a
panindia empire the Maratas liberated
India from the Turk occupation the
Marata Empire brought back Hinduisi
Swarajia they liberated Baratwash
sadly the British defeated the Maratas
and that's where we that's be and that's
because because of that we are where we
are today. Right. Right. Okay. Next.
Sai Bablu says, "How did our
civilization treat or or view the
disabled people since its starting
days?"
Um disabled people.
So from it's it's a nuanced perspective.
See, we believe in karma, right? Our
culture believes in karma. What is
karma? It's a conservation law. It's the
law of conservation of cause and effect
over multiple lifetimes. That's the law
of karma. It's a conservation law.
It's Yeah. That's interesting. Now um so
according to the law of karma, if you
are born with certain characteristics,
it's because of your actions in past
lives. So if you're super powerful,
strong and you know great, fantastic
person with super intelligence, great
looks and all that, it's because you did
fantastic great deeds in your past life
and that's why you've been rewarded with
these characteristics today. It's not
like you do do something naughty in this
life, next life you will be born as an
ant or a fly. It's not like that. That
is a superficial silly way of looking at
it. Karma is sophisticated.
So um so if your positive
characteristics are the outcome or the
fruit of good actions in your past lives
then if you born with vicris or defects
or disabilities maybe you did something
naughty or nasty in in previous
lifetimes and you are paying for that by
suffering through these disabilities in
this current lifetime to pay off the
karmic rena or debt. That's how that's
one way of looking at karma at a
disability. But that doesn't mean that
you discriminate against disabled
people. Disability doesn't mean that you
have to have a bad life. For example, in
the rigid there is the mention of this
uh queen who fought a battle. Her name
was Vishala.
And in the course of the battle, she
lost a leg. So she goes back outside of
the battlefield. She has her doctors
stitch her up and they give her a
prosthetic leg and she puts the
prosthetic leg on. The the bleeding is
stopped. The prosthetic leg leg is put
on and she goes back into the battle.
the first ever literary example of a
prosthetic limb in human history. So
Vish Palpala became disabled but she
that did not prevent her from going back
and performing a duty. Uh another
example is the sage the rishi ashtavakra
who had eight disabilities but he is
regarded as one of the great rishies
right ashtavakra. Then you have the
example of dtarashtra.
So darraashtra is the son of what? Pandu
is it? There was the son there was the
son of
his brother was Pandu. Uh I may not have
the details right. So he was blind. He
was born blind and uh because of that he
could not become the king and his
brother became the king but his brother
eventually abdicated the throne which is
whyra had to become the king in place of
his brother and he was blind. So despite
being blind he became the king and he
had good advisers. He had Bishma he had
he had Duryodhan he had Sanjay who could
who could act as his eyes and his his
very loyal wife she decided to blind for
herself herself for the rest of her life
because her husband did not have the
facility of sight and solidarity with
him. So Darashtra despite being blind
was treated very well in society and so
on. So you have many examples in Indian
history where people who are disabled
are treated well. In the autastra there
are specific punishments for people who
discriminate against against disabled
people and there are various provisions
for the for for enabling disabled people
to live a good life you know. So India
has always taken care of disabled
people. India has never discriminated
against disabled people disabled in
various ways. So that's how we have
treated disabled people. I think no
civilization historically has treated
disabled people the way we have
historically. Today it's a different
story. Today the west claims to be super
disability friendly and all
but we were the OGs like they say right?
Okay we've crossed two overs. I had made
a promise I made a promise Mr. Frodo I
mean I made a promise in a previous live
stream that I would take up this one
physics question that uh our friend has
asked. So I will take up this one
physics question and then I will take up
some questions from the live chat. So
what is this physics question that
Shvatza asked us. So Shivatza said that
let's say you have a neutron star and
you take out a piece of neutron star
that is the size of a grain of sand.
A neutron star
it's got the mass it's got a mass that
is more than that of the sun but it is
compressed into a diameter of about 20
km that is shockingly dense that is more
than nuclear density and that's why what
you have in a neutron star is mainly
neutrons only. It has a thin atmosphere
of iron plasma and inside you've got
strange very weird matter called which
is considered which is called nuclear
pasta and all but overall it's nuclear
density extremely extremely dense
incredibly dense so what if you take a
tiny bit of a neutron star the size of a
grain of sand and you somehow are able
to transport it to earth and you release
it into the earth's atmosphere what
happens is the question that is the big
question it's a fantastic thought
experiment. So if you take this sand
grain piece of neutron star, bring it
into the earth's atmosphere, release it
there, will it remain intact? It won't
remain intact. See, outside of the
gravity that a neutron star provides,
that bit of material is violently
unstable. It will decompress
explosively. It will turn into an
exploding fireball, a a ball of plasma.
Okay. And it will be made of neutronrich
matter and a tremendous amount of energy
will be released. Much of it will will
be released in the form of neutrinos
most of which are harmless. But the
tremendous amount of energy. So the
question is how much energy is released
in terms ter terms of kilotons of TNT.
So look roughly the density of a neutron
star is about 10 to 17 kilogram per
cubic meter.
That's one with 17 zeros after it. Those
many kilograms per cubic meter. So the
mass of a neutron, so the mass, okay, if
you take a grain of sand, let's say half
a millimeter, then its mass of that
little bit of material is about 20
million kilogram.
It's the mass of an iceberg,
medium-sized iceberg. And how many
nucleons does it contain? it it will
contain about 10 to 34 nucleons and
assuming that the energy released per
nucleon is about 10 mega electron volts
you will find that the output energetic
output is of the order of 10 ra to 22
jew
if you convert that into terms in in
terms of tons of TNT or kilotons of TNT
or gigatons you find that that's about
5,000 gigatons of TNT day 5,000 gat tons
of TNT assuming 10 um assuming uh 10 me
per nucleon. So what is 5,000 gat tons
of TNT?
The most powerful
nuclear weapon ever tested
was the Sar Bomba
Russian weapon. its energy output was 50
megat tons of TNT.
So one sand grain sized
bit of of neutron star matter matter
will give you 5,000 gigatons of TNT that
is one lakh sar bombas 100,000 sar
bombas
another way of comparing
the chickik shalub impact event that
killed off the non-avian dinosaurs it
gave off about 10 to 23 jewels
So the so the the the
5,000 gat tons it's about roughly 1/5 of
that. So if you release a sand grain
piece sand grain sized piece of neutron
star matter into the earth's atmosphere
it's going to have a very similar effect
as the chik shalob impact event. It is
not a city killer it's a planet killer.
It will cause an extinction event. It'll
be a disaster. Imagine that a sand grain
sized bit of neutron star matter you
release it into into the atmosphere it
will devastate the world it will cause
an extinction event similar to the
asteroid that killed off the non-avian
dinosaurs that's how frightful this is
this is all order of magnitude
calculations I'm not giving you exact
calculations because you can't really
estimate everything properly but it's
about 5,000 gatons maybe 4,000 gatons
around you know that sort of uh ballpark
we talking about. Okay, I still have
many more questions, but I won't be able
to take them because we've crossed two
over. So, let's take some questions from
the live chat. Let me take some
questions from the live chat. If you
have any questions, please go ahead and
ask me some. Um, Aush Singh says,
"Europeans claim a protoindop European
Indo-Uropean language existed uh 6 7,000
years ago evolving into Sanskrit linked
to island migration. Share your
knowledge." I kind of did speak about
this tangentially. So when the Europeans
arrived in India a few centuries ago,
they discovered that you know what the
Sanskrit language seems to be very
similar to our Greek and Latin languages
and Sanskrit is far older. So clearly
the people of India speak a language
that is closely related to Greece
language of Greece and the language of
Italy original language of Italy which
is Latin and also similar to German,
French, all the various European
languages.
So clearly this would potentially
indicate that all these people share the
same ancestry going back many thousand
years. That would indicate that all
these languages evolved from a common
shared language some which was very
ancient very old and which may have
existed 5 6 7 8,000 years ago. And they
they called this the protoindo-uropean
language. Earlier it was called the
protoarian language but then the arian
the word Arian became evil right because
the Nazis used it. So now it's called
the protoindo-uropean language. It makes
sense. Yeah, it makes sense that the
theories makes sense. The logic makes
sense. The question is what is the
identity of the ancient the original
language that was the mother language of
all the Indo-Uropean languages that
exist today? They claim there was some
protoindouropean language. They claim
that Sanskrit and and and Persian are
sister languages. They make all these
distortions. In my opinion, the
protoindo-uropean language is
protoanskrit, the older version of
Sanskrit, the pre-wdic Sanskrit. That's
how I see it. They don't see it that way
and they don't agree, but okay. Right.
Okay.
Next question.
Um
hey [laughter]
creative clips says did Abrahamic
religions like Christianity and Islam um
form because of Buddhism?
Um
Christianity
came before Islam. Before Christianity
came Judaism. Judaism was originally
polytheistic by the way
and then somehow it becomes
monotheistic. There is this movie called
the man from earth or something 2009 or
something around that time. Let's let's
let's let's Google it shall we? The man
from earth
uh the man from earth 2007 is it? Okay
2007. Yeah this one.
[laughter]
So in this in this movie there's this
guy who says that he has been around for
like several thousand years. He doesn't
die and he says that he he went to India
and learned Buddhism and then he went to
Europe several thousand like 2,000 years
ago trying to spread Buddhism in Europe
and he inadvertently became the catalyst
of the of the introduction of
Christianity into Europe because the
Buddhist precepts became they were
converted into Christianity.
Um, it is possible.
It is very possible that Christianity
is nothing but repackaged Buddhism.
Very possible. I will have to look into
that in detail because I've acquired a
new book somewhere. Where is it? It's by
a gentleman called Joseph Nun and I have
yet to read it. But very interesting
um yeah idea. So I think it's it's
certainly something we would take
seriously.
Right. Uh
field strong man is talking about
geopolitics. Now that the word deep
state, the term deep set has gone
mainstream. Do you get bored of the
repetitive question on deep state in
super chats? I I I
look it is to a large extent the fault
of these uh these YouTubers raia this
that they sensationalize everything and
they've they've turned this word into
the straight overused term
right
u I obviously am not the biggest fan of
repetitive questions the same questions
asked over and over again but the thing
about super chats is that they at least
ask better questions.
Yeah. Okay. Okay. We have super chats. I
did not realize we have super chats.
Okay. Spain is a new member. Welcome,
sir. Thank you so much for becoming a
member. Mr. Sid says says people say the
Middle East is united under Islam, but
the reality is that they all hate each
other. Iran, Saudi, Syrians,
Palestinians all hate each other. What's
my opinion? Look, it's complicated. Um,
you may have the same religion, but you
have different territories and you have
different agendas. You have different
national aspirations. You've got
different agendas and you've got
different ideas of how the world should
be and you may have territorial
disputes. You may have old blood feuds
so much more. You may be Shia, you may
be Sunni once that was also a factor,
right? Um
so yeah to to a large extent you have
this issue in the Middle East. You have
the same religion but it's not like
they're all united. Many of them are
rivals. Iran, Saudi Arabia are big
rivals. Palestinians, nobody wants them.
Everybody wants to support Palestine.
Nobody wants to
give refuge to Palestinian refugees in
their country. Nobody wants to do that.
So no one likes Palestinians for some
reason. Syria a whole different issue.
So you're right to a large extent it's
like that. Arjun says you should
criticize the corrupt. What does this
have to do with history sir? We are
discussing history. I should do a lot of
things
but I can't fight every fight.
Do you expect Roger Federer to now
decide that he will fight the go and
play cricket?
Do you expect Virat Kohli to start
playing hockey tomorrow? You have to
pick and choose your field and your
domains and stick to that. You can't go
and fight every goddamn fight in the
world. So please understand,
I discuss history, geopolitics, science.
This is a whole different subject. That
is not my fight. That is my choice. I
have chosen to focus on these three
things. These are very big things.
History, geopolitics, science, huge,
huge disciplines, huge domains.
So I am not venturing into other things.
Rahul says recently saw Canara was
disgusted how they portrayed slavery in
our culture for building temples low-key
adharmic things. How true are they? We
never had slavery in Bharat. Never.
Slavery is not a concept that ever
existed in Indian civilization. I
haven't seen Canara or Canara 2 or
whatever this is. I don't watch these
movies. They people may praise them or
whatever. I don't watch them. I know
that I will be super disappointed when I
watch these things. So I spare myself
that misery and pain. I don't watch any
of this. Uh so I I don't know what is
ported in there. I've seen the trailers
and all. I I said okay it is best I stay
away from this. Um
if they have portrayed slavery and all
that then they are doing us our our
history and our ancestors a great
disservice. They're doing our people a
great disservice. They are doing our
future a great disservice and they have
may have or may not have may be may not
be some kind of agenda behind it. That's
all I can say. I haven't seen it myself.
Um Ritik Praar says this is the
hypothetical question.
What do you think might have happened if
the painter had acquired New York before
the US? Would he have won World War II?
If yes, how would the world look? If he
had acquired New York before the US, he
would have won World War II in that
case. Everyone would be speaking German
today
or something like that. That's what the
world order would look like kind of. You
see, and it would be totally different.
Maybe North America would be German
speaking. Maybe north North America
would be partitioned between a German
speaking region and a Japanese speaking
region. Who knows? Anything could have
happened. Can't can't really say.
Ankita says
uh what were the reasons for the
scientific and technological progress
prowess prowess of Nazi Germany during
the second world war?
The reasons for the for the incredible
tremendous scientific and technological
prowess of Germany during this period of
time was the groundwork laid in the
1800s.
See Germany was unified for the first
time in its history in 1871 by the iron
chancellor Utafon Bismar. So Germany was
created as this artificial nation which
never existed before. You never had
something called Deutschand before. So
it was created in 1871 and the German
empire
it consciously focused on technological
excellence on the best education system
the world could ever have anywhere
and industry science technology
engineering industry all based on the
best education system in the world. They
consciously went after this and they
created these robust academic
institutions which were all entirely
based on merit and excellence and
research output and that's why quantum
mechanics came out of Germany. That's
why so many of these advancements came
out of Germany and that's why Germany
was the pioneer of the cruise missile of
the ballistic missile of the jet engine
of the flying wing design which is not
the stealth bomber and so many more
things. Germany was the pioneer of all
these things because of the outstanding
robust excellent education system that
they had fully research based fully
focused on science and technology not on
the humanities and all that nonsense
they had that also but separate
and it was purely merit-based that's why
Germany became a scientific
technological and military superpower it
was a culture of excellence and merit
MK says did India have its version of
the pelponian war? No, we didn't have
that. We never had city states and
stuff. So not we did not have it. What
is history of women education before the
British? Says Aayush Arjunov. Women
wrote the rigida. Women were super
educated. Women had the same rights as
men. Boys and girls got the same
education. Women became rishies or
rishikas.
like 30 40 50% of the verses of the
rigid I'm not sure what the percentage
is were written by women
so that's what we had before the British
the British ruined everything
uh Pakistan's richest man says namaste
yes namaste was Buddhism truly a non-
Brahim royal response to Brahmin le
Hinduism or is is that just the modern
framing Buddhism was an obscure
fringe movement
it was not a response to Brahim
ical patriarchy or brahminical operation
or any other thing. This is all modern
framing. RC Majunar introduced the term
brahminism. What is brahminism?
This is a fake modern
word that's been that's been thrust upon
us. It was dharma. It was Hindu dharma.
There was the brahinss were not super
powerful people who led the world or
something, right? and and Goautam Buddha
was essentially going against the grain
and he wanted to create a different
movement and uh that's what it did and
the point is that it was completely
fringe. It was completely obscure. No
one knew about it but Ashoke,
Emperor Ashoke brought it to prominence
for political reasons
and he turned this obscure fringe
movement into a global phenomenon.
Right? Um and then the Buddhists went
after the brahinss. They portrayed the
brahinss as what
uh as violent people as as people who
sacrificed animals and who you know all
kinds of propaganda was done against the
brahinss
and for a long time you know for several
centuries Buddhism became the the major
flavor of dharma in India until
Adishankaria
once again brought the vic you know way
of life back in in India. So all of
these things that we are taught, it's
all modern framing. It's all hindophobic
framing essentially.
Um Amisha says, "How did Rome keep track
of who is free versus who is slave?" Um
I'm not sure.
I suppose they would have they would
have had a bureaucracy with records and
records and things. Maybe every rich
person who was a slave owner would have
records of who were the slaves, when
they were bought, when they were born,
to whom they were sold, from whom they
were bought for, how much they were
brought for bought for and so on. I
suppose all of those records would have
existed, but I am not aware of the
details.
Uh, feline lover, well, thank you so
much. No question, but thank you so much
once again. All right, so that brings us
to the end of today's session. I know
there's way more questions that you all
have, but I'm going to have to end it
over here. Can't do eight hour live
streams every every single time. So, I'm
going to end it here. And tomorrow,
we're going to have a live stream that
in which I will discuss geopolitics.
I'll take your questions from the super
chat. I look forward to seeing you all
there. There is a lot happening in
geopolitics. A lot that is very
important. So there's a lot to discuss
and I look forward to doing you the
doing that with you all tomorrow. Please
ask me your best questions and we will
discuss the most important issues of the
day. Thank you everybody. Keep asking
questions. Keep learning. Never stop
learning. Keep raising your standards
and I'll see you tomorrow. Take care.
Thank you. Good day. Goodbye. Good
night. See you tomorrow.